Finding aid for the Nikki R. Keddie papers LSC.1789
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nikki R. Keddie papers
1947-2003
UCLA Library Special Collections
Keddie, Nikki R., 1930-
LSC.1789
15.8 Linear Feet (33 boxes, 4 flat boxes, 1 oversize flat box)
Nikki Keddie is Professor Emeritus in the Department of History. Keddie taught Middle Eastern and Iranian history at UCLA. Her research focused on Iran, Islam, Middle Eastern women, and comparative world history. This collection, spanning 1947 to 2003, consists of materials related to Keddie's teaching career and academic research. The papers include UCLA Department of History files, correspondence, conference materials, manuscript drafts, and research materials. Lastly, the collection includes photographic slides taken by Keddie throughout her career documenting research that heavily feature countries such as Iran, Indonesia, Morocco, Pakistan, Tunisa, and Senegal; as well as European cities, Los Angeles and other parts of the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Nikki R. Keddie, 2009 through 2011.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9981840843606533
Biography/History
Anita Nikki (Ragozin) Keddie was born August 30, 1930 in Brooklyn, New York. Keddie attended City and Country School and Horace-Mann Lincoln High School in Manhattan. She attended Radcliffe College, receiving a BA in Modern European History and Literature in 1951 (Radcliffe College functioned as a female coordinate institution for the all-male Harvard College. A merger with Harvard began in 1977). Keddie was elected to Phi Beta Kappa in her junior year and wrote her thesis on the Italian Socialist Party. Keddie then received her MA in Modern European History from Stanford University in 1951, writing a thesis on Giambattista Vico's philosophy of history. She received her PhD in History (Modern European, especially Middle Eastern, with lesser emphasis on East and South Asia) from the University of California, Berkeley, with a dissertation titled, "The Impact of the West on Modern Iranian Social History."
After completing her doctorate, Keddie held the following positions: adjunct professor at the University of Arizona (1957); instructor and then assistant professor at Scripps College (1957-1961); and visiting professor (1961), assistant professor (1963), and then associate and full professor at UCLA in the Department of History, retiring in 1993 as Professor Emeritus. Keddie taught Middle Eastern and Iranian history at UCLA, as well as courses on comparative revolution, comparative religious politics, and non-written sources and methodology in history research. Her research focused on Iran, Islam, Middle Eastern women, and Sayyid Jamal al-Din al-Afghani. Afghani was a political activist and Islamic ideologist during the late 19th century.
Keddie founded and edited the journal Contention: Debates in Society, Culture and Science (1991-1996) and published many monographs including: Women in the Middle East: Past and Present (2007), Modern Iran: Roots and Results of Revolution (2003, Revised Edition 2006), Qajar Iran and the Rise of Reza Khan (1999), Iran and the Muslim World: Resistance and Revolution (1995). Roots of Revolution: An Interpretive History of Modern Iran (1981), Iran: Religion, Politics and Society (1980), Sayyid Jamal al-Din "al-Afghani": A Political Biography (1972), and Religion and Rebellion in Iran: The Tobacco Protest of 1891-92 (1966).
Some of Keddie's awards and honors include: Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences (1994); Mentoring Award, Middle East Studies Association (2001); Honorary Fellow, Middle East Studies Association (2003); Scholarly Distinction, American Historical Association (2001); Persian History Award, Encyclopedia Iranica Foundation (2002); and Distinguished Lifetime Achievement Award, International Society for Iranian Studies (2008).
Scope and Content
This collection consists of materials related to the teaching career and academic research of Nikki Keddie, UCLA Professor Emerita of History. The papers include UCLA Department of History files, correspondence, conference materials, manuscript drafts, and research materials. Lastly, the collection includes photographic slides taken by Keddie throughout her career and as part of her research that heavily feature countries with large Muslim populations, such as Iran, Indonesia, Morocco, Pakistan, Tunisa, and Senegal; as well as European cities, Los Angeles and other parts of the United States.
Organization and Arrangement
This collections been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Subject and administrative files, 1947-2003
Subseries 1.1: Biographical and academic appointments, 1947-2003
Subseries 1.2: Correspondence, 1948-1997
Subseries 1.2: Conferences and professional societies, 1955-2003
Series 2: Publications, 1957-2003
Subseries 2.1: Works by Keddie, 1957-2003
Subseries 2.2: Reviews of Keddie's published works, 1967-2003
Subseries 2.3: Contention, 1989-1996
Series 3: Research files, circa 1950-2003
Series 4: Photographic materials, 1958-1997
Materials are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Photography -- History -- Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles. Department of History--Faculty -- Archives
- Series 1: Subject and administrative files., 1947-2003
  Scope and Content
  This series contains materials related to Keddie's academic work at UCLA as well as other universities. It consists of biographical materials, publisher files, correspondence, academic conference and professional society files. This series offers insight into Keddie's involvement within the UCLA Department of History and the greater academic community.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this series will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  - Subseries 1.1: Biographical and academic appointments., 1947-2003
    This subseries includes materials largely related to Keddie's academic work, including biographic materials, publisher files, fellowships, and UCLA files. The UCLA files concern courses Keddie taught, History department administrative files, and student advising. The subseries also features materials related Keddie's art collection and expertise in Middle Eastern art history.
    COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this subseries will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Art history and collections., 1947-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographies. Works by Keddie., 1978-1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bibliographies. Research and course reading lists., circa 1970-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Biographical materials., 1965-2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Book publicity materials., 1972-2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Book royalties., 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Calendar., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Calendar., 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Clippings. About Keddie., 1976, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Collected biographies., 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Curriculum vitae., 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Fowler Museum. Qashqa'i exhibition donation materials., 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship., 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Gustav E. von Grunebaum Center for Near Eastern Studies., 1982-1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - KPFK talk and music recording. Compact audio cassette., circa 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      COLLECTION CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this file will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    - Lecture notes. Photography for the Social Sciences., undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters of recommendation by Keddie., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Los Angeles County Museum of Art (LACMA) donation materials., 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - North Africa trip., 1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Obituary for Dr. Gustave E. von Grunebaum., 1992 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Photographs of Keddie., undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Photographs, untitled., undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Photography notes., 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Portrait sketch., undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Publications. Keddie is cited., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Publications. Keddie is featured., 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Publisher contracts and agreements., 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Publisher correspondence, articles, and other materials., 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Report on the Handicrafts and the Handicrafts Center in Iran., 1974 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Research proposals and reports., circa 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Tourism materials., circa 1949-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - UCLA. Course descriptions, funding applications, and conference materials., 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - UCLA. Course descriptions, syllabi, and other materials., circa 1966-1996 (Box 2, Folder 9-11)
    - UCLA. Faculty Committee on the Status of Women., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - UCLA. Grievance statement., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - UCLA. Hammer lecture., 1999 March 18 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - UCLA. History Department files., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - UCLA. News and events., 1965-1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - UCLA. Request for Advancement to Step V., 1978 September 24 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - UCLA. Student Advising., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - UCLA. Student work: Aghaie, Kamran., 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - University newsletters., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Women's history materials., circa 1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 1.2: Correspondence., 1948-1997
    This subseries contains Keddie's general and research correspondence. Most of the correspondence is professional in subject, including matters related to research travel, funding, publications, article reviews, and academic appointments. The subseries has retained Keddie's original filing system, organized first by subject and then chronologically. The only exception is the Carlo Poni file, which is correspondence between Keddie and Poni on personal and professional matters.
    - Correspondence. Afghani, Jamal al-din al-, circa 1960-1996 (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
    - Correspondence. Daedalus., 1969 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence. Funding., circa 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence. Iran., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence. Personal., 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence. Poni, Carlo., 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence. Publishers., 1966-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. Professional references., 1964-1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence. UC Berkeley sabbatical., 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence. UCLA., 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence. Vietnam War protests., 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence., 1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence., 1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence., circa 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence., 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence., 1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence., 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence., 1956 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence., 1959 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence., 1961 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence., 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence., 1965 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence., 1966 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence., 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence., 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence., 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence., 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence., 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence., undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 1.3: Conferences and professional societies., 1955-2003
    This subseries contains conference announcements, programs, handwritten notes, papers presented with annotations, and proposals. It also includes materials related to Keddie's memberships to professional societies, such as announcements, newsletters, and journals.
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences., 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - American Historical Association., 1955-2002 (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
    - American Institute of Iranian Studies., 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - American Oriental Society., 1961, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Asian and Islam conferences., 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Asia Society Project on Islam and Public Life in Asia., 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Association for Asian Studies., 1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Association for the Study of Persianate Societies., 2003 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Berlin Conference on Muslim Migration to Cities., 1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Biennial Conference on Iranian Studies., 1998 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Comparative Politics: Research Perspectives for the Next 20 Years., 1988 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Conference on Comparative Fundamentalism., 1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Conference programs and announcements. Assorted., 1968-2002 (Box 6, Folder 11-15)
    - Conference notes., circa 1980-1995 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Conference proposals., undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Fundamentalism conference list., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Globalization, Political Islam and Urban Social Movements., 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Gulf/2000 Project., 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Human Rights and Civil Liberties in Iran., 1982 May 22 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - International Colloquium in 18th Century Renewal and Reform Movements in Islam., 1985 June (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - International Economic History Conference., undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Iran lectures, correspondence, and program lists., 1955-1997 (Box 7, Folder 9-11)
    - Iran and the Surrounding World Since 1500., 2000 April (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Iran, the US, and the USSR., 1988 April (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Iran: 25 Centuries of Achievement., 1971 October (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Library of Congress: Looking Back to the Future., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Middle Eastern Studies Association., 1967-2001 (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
    - Middle East Women's Studies., 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Montclair State College: Iran, the Middle East and the Decade of the 1990s., 1991 October 25 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Neither East nor West: Iran, US, USSR., 1989 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Pakistan trip and programs., 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Photographic Society International., 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Princeton University: Near Eastern Studies Department., 1974 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - RAND Center: Middle East Conference., 1992-1994 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Safavid Conference., 1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Social Sciences and Problems of Development: Iran., 1974 June (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Society for Iranian Studies., 1974-2000 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - State, Society, and Economy in 19th Century Iran Conference., 1978 June (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - University of Sussex: Subordination of Women Project, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Publications., 1957-2003
  This series contains published works and materials related to those works that are authored/co-authored or edited by Keddie, including articles, book chapters, and the journal Contention: Debates in Society, Culture and Science. It also includes reviews of Keddie's books. Much of her work centers around Iranian history, Sayyed Jamal ad-Din al-Afghani, Middle Eastern women, and religious and political trends in Iran and the Muslim world. Afghani was a political activist and Islamic ideologist during the late 19th century. The materials are titled with variants of his name, including Al-Afghani, ad-Din Asadabadi, and Jamal al-Din al Afghani, in accordance to the creator's own file and notes titles.
  - Subseries 2.1: Works by Keddie., 1957-2003
    This subseries contains Keddie's numerous authored and co-authored articles and book chapters. It also includes correspondence, Keddie's notes, and manuscript abstracts and drafts with annotations.
    - Afghani, Jamal ad-din al- articles., 1965-1973 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Background of the Constitutional Movement in Azerbaijan., 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Bausani abstract., 1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Book jackets and covers., 1973-1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Contributions of Vladimir Gordlevsky to the Study of the Seljuk Turks in Asia Minor., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Crisis in Communism and the Middle East., 2002 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Economics articles., 1957-1989 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Encyclopedia of the Modern Islamic World. Multiple entries., 1992 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Encyclopedia of the Modern Middle East. Style guide., 1988 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Encylcopedia of Political Revolutions. Edited by Keddie., 1998 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - From Senegal to Sumatra and Between: Comparative Studies in History and Society., 1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Fundamentalism project., 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Iran articles., 1968-1979 (Box 9, Folder 20, Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Iran book proposal., 1997 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Iran: A Brief History Since 1500., 1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Iran, Islam articles., 1969-1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Iran: 1978 Revolution., circa 1980-1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Iranian Constitutional Revolution of 1905-1911., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Iranian Constitutional Revolution., circa 1996 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Iranian Imbroglios: Who's Irrational?, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Islamist Movement in Tunisia., 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Islamic Philosophy and Islamic Modernism., 1967 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Journal of Women's History., 1995-1997 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Le Monde articles., 1977, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Los Angeles Times articles., 1980-1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Messianism and Revolt in Modern Iran., 1998 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Methodology articles., 1973-1984 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Middle East articles., circa 1980-1994 (Box 10, Folder 16, Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Orientalism., 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Pakistan articles., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Proto-Capitalism: Japan and Europe, with Comparisons to East Asia and the Middle East., 1999 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Qashwai Tribal Confederation of Iran, circa 1979 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Religion and Rule in Iran., 1995 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Reviews by Keddie., 1965-2002 (Box 11, Folder 7-10)
    - Revolution and Post-Revolution in Iran in Comparative Perspective., 1997 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Rise of Islam as a Force in International Affairs., 1981 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Secularism articles., 1994-1996 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Surfeit of Satans. Los Angeles Times Opinion article., 1991 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Western Rules Versus Western Values., 1959 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Why Didn't We Speak Up Sooner?, circa 1986 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Why has Iran Been Revolutionary?, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Women, Gender, and Fundamentalism Worldwide., 1995 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Women in Iran Since 1979., 2000 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Women in Islam articles., circa 1977-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Women in the Middle East., 1979-2001 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 2.2: Reviews of Keddie's published works., 1967-2003
    This subseries includes copies and printouts of academic and popular reviews of Keddie's published works, including her books Iran and the Muslim World, Root and Revolution, and Sayyid Jamal Ad-Din Al-Afghani.
    - Assorted reviews of Keddie's books., 1969-2003 (Box 12, Folder 3-5)
    - Iran and the Muslim World., 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Islamic Response to Imperialism., 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Religion and Rebellion in Iran., 1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Roots of Revolution., 1978-1984 (Box 12, Folder 10-12)
    - Sayyid Jamal Ad-Din Al-Aghani., 1973-1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Scholars, Saints, and Sufis., 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Women in the Muslim World., 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2.3: Contention., 1989-1996
    Contention: Debates in Society, Culture and Science was a journal founded and edited by Keddie from 1991 to 1996. The journal was published by the Indiana University Press. It's mission was to present significant controversies and trends in the social sciences and humanities fields. Materials in this subseries include correspondence, address lists, reviews, proposals, articles, and funding documents related to the journal.
    - Acceptance letters., 1989 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
    - Address lists., circa 1990 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
    - Article reviews., 1990-1991 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Bellagio Study and Conference Center., 1992 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Biographies., circa 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Clippings., 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Contention fund., 1990-1996 (Box 13, Folder 12-13)
    - Correspondence. Outgoing., 1989-1991 (Box 14, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence. Incoming., 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence. Indiana University Press., circa 1990-1996 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Debating Revolutions issue., 1994 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Editor requests., 1989 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Indiana University Press materials., 1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Journal mockup., 1991 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Lists of editors, advisory board, contributors, and subscribers., circa 1989-1994 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Pending articles and reviewers., 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Proposals and announcements., circa 1989-1992 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Rejected articles., 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Rejection letters., 1989 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Subsidy presses., 1989-1990 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Research files., circa 1950-2003
  Publications, typed and handwritten notes, literature reviews, outlines, manuscripts, and other materials related to Keddie's academic research. A large portion of her research focused on Iran, Islam, Middle Eastern women, and Sayyid Jamal al-Din al-Afghani. Afghani was a political activist and Islamic ideologist during the late 19th century. Some of the materials related to Afghani are in Arabic. The materials are titled with variants of his name, including Al-Afghani, ad-Din Asadabadi, and Jamal al-Din al Afghani, in accordance to the creator's own file and notes titles.
  - Afary, Janet publications., 1989-1995 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Afghani, Sayyid Jamal al-Din al- research materials and notes., circa 1950-1983 (Box 15, Folder 10-11, Box 16, Folder 1-11)
  - Africa notes and clippings., 1985 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Algeria research materials., 1964-1981 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Arabic language notes., 1960 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Clippings. Iran., 1968-1997 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)